搞屁啊
You've got to be shitting me.
靠
Oh, shit!
让路
Get out of the way!
- 瞎开 - 靠
- Driving all crazy. - Damn.
16号车 徒步追捕一号男性
16. I've got a foot chase on a number-one male.
约13岁 矮个 扎小辫
Maybe 13 years, short, with braids,
在Fulton街后巷向东移动
in the alleys eastbound from Fulton.
那孩子弃车了 弃车了
This kid has bailed out! Bailed out!
操 操 操 操 操
Motherfucking fuck fuck fuck fuck!
警官 你搞什么
Officer, what are you doing?
干嘛 你要不要戴眼镜啊
What, you need bifocals or something?
什么
What?
9号车 我正赶往事发地
0-9. I'm responding.
16号 200北
16, 200 north.
告诉我你名字
I'm gonna need your name.
听着 女士 我很抱歉
Listen. I'm very sorry, ma'am, all right?
帽子给我
Give me the hat.
他们的远征困难重重
Nah, see, them Expeditions are hard to handle.
但要有雷克萨斯 对我来说不在话下
But with a Lexus, man I wouldn't have no problem.
小杂种
You little motherfucker.
- 你知道自己撞了多少辆车吗 - 什么
- You know how many cars you hit? - What?
别给我打马虎眼
Don't even think of bullshitting.
不知道你说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你知道我他妈有多少报告要写吗
You know what kind of fucking paperwork I got now, huh?
你知道你他妈浪费了我多少时间吗 小鬼
You know how many hours of my life you owe me, you little shit?
靠 疼
Damn, yo! That hurt!
这就疼了...
You think that hurts...
不 不要
No, no. Aah!
你这么聪明
You're so smart,
偷车很轻松呢
- see how easy you boost a car now. - Aah!
火线重案组 第四季 第10集
the.wire.s04e10
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
世界往一个方向 人往另一个方向 --Poot
你能想象Rawls坐上这把椅子吗
You imagine Rawls sitting in this chair?
没门 在这儿 哼哼
Never happen. In this town: Uh-uh.
我们本来还不该出现白人市长呢
Yeah, well, we weren't supposed to have a white mayor, either.
他让Rawls主事已经过火了
He already overreached putting Rawls in charge.
的他妈的确
De-fucking-facto.
那混蛋还没宣誓就职就这样了
Motherfucker ain't even sworn in yet.
他已经广布眼线了
Already, he's got feelers out.
我知道他给我朋友 匹兹堡的副局长
I know for a fact he called the deputy chief in Pittsburgh--
打了电话
Friend of mine--
许以重金
promised him pie in the sky.
靠 哥们
Shi-it, partner.
你要做的就是让Carcetti和其他人看到
All you got to do is show Carcetti and everybody else
这位子就该你坐
that they already got the man for the job.
他们就不要再有什么想法了
They ain't got to look no further.
你是不可或缺的
The indispensable man.
以前是Royce拖你后腿 Ervin
It was Royce holding you back, Ervin.
现在你自由了
Now out from under, you shine.
Clay 他说所有事情都要通过Bill Rawls
Clay, he's saying everything goes through Bill Rawls.
- 我稍一动弹... - 你还是局长 不对吗
- Any move I try to make-- - You're still the commissioner, ain't you?
下面都得听你的
You give an order, they gonna jump.
- 是 但Carcetti... - 他能把你怎样 炒了你?
- Yeah, but Carcetti-- - What he gonna do, fire you?
你也看到了 他没这胆子
He just showed you he don't have balls enough.
你只需给Carcetti做出点成绩
You just need to give Carcetti a little something.
让他对你另眼相看
Make him start seeing you in a new light.
比如呢
Like what:
一些警察该做的事 靠 我怎么知道
Some kind of police shit. Hell, I don't know.
一些Carcetti看得上眼的事
Something that looks good to Carcetti,
那他就可以说让你留下是他的想法
so he can say it was his idea to keep you all along.
嗯
Hmm.
警察该做的事
Police shit:
怎样都好 你们就是吃这行饭的嘛
Well, whatever it is y'all do for a living.
这样
Well--
你尽人事
just take care of your end
其他的交给你朋友们办
and let your friends handle theirs.
早上好
Good morning.
我刚刚把东西放教室里
I just dropped my stuff in my room,
维护人员和Donnelly在那检查暖气
and maintenance and Donnelly are in there checking the heat.
里面起码有80度(摄氏30度)
It must be 80 degrees in there.
90分钟课程
90-minute classes.
什么
Excuse me:
今年这阶段我们要上90分钟的课程
This time of the year, we go to 90-minute classes.
恶补数学和语文
Concentrated prep in math and language arts only.
不明白 跟暖气什么关系
I don't follow. Why the heat?
只有这样才能让孩子们坐上90分钟
It's the only way the kids will sit through 90 minutes of anything.
- 让他们昏昏欲睡? - 对
- Make them drowsy? - Right.
就是为了考试咯
So it's about the tests.
从现在开始到他们准备好
From now until they're done,
一切都是为考试服务
everything's about the tests.
靠
Damn!
冬天我要去暖和点的地方
I ought to go somewhere warm for the winter.
哪儿
Where?
我在"动物星球"上看到的
I saw on "Animal Planet"
捕枪鱼
marlin fishing--
比如佛罗里达 巴哈马
Iike, Florida, the Bahamas.
那玩意看起来很好吃
That shit looked sweet.
那里的水...
The water was like this...
那颜色
this color, man.
伙计 今年不会那么冷
Man, it ain't gonna be that cold this year.
你怎么知道
How you know?
- 全球变暖啊 - 那为什么现在就冷成这样了
- Global warming. - So why is it so cold already?
是我们老了
Yo, we just getting old.
那倒是
Yeah. True that.
你他妈上哪儿去了
Yo. Where the fuck you been?
市监狱里待了一天半
City jail for a day and a half
直到他们给我做好记录
till they recogged me.
接着我奶奶病了 就在那待了一会
Then my grandma got sick, so I was over there for a while.
条子指控你什么了吗
Po-Po hit you with a charge, huh?
小罪名
Just a humble--
假口供什么的
false statement and shit,
因为我假装不是我
for saying I wasn't who I really was.
靠 那他们为什么那么急着找你
Damn, so why they was asking about you like that?
- 嗯哼 - 他们想问你话?
- Hmm-mmm. - They try talking to you?
关于谋杀的
Yeah, about some murder.
- 哪桩 - 哪桩都无所谓
- Which one? - It don't matter which murder
反正我什么也没告诉那帮混球
because I didn't say shit to them bitches, though.
你不用跟我说
Yeah, well, I ain't the one you need to convince.
- 我干嘛要跟他说 - 我就说说
- Why I got to convince him? - You know, I'm saying, yo.
警察来找你 把你带走
Po-Po come asking about you, they snatch your ass up,
失踪个几天
you out of pocket for a few days.
他当然会有所耳闻
Heh! Oh, yeah. He'll definitely hear about it.
我什么都没说
I didn't say nothing to nobody.
所以他们才给我安了个小罪名
That's why they gave me the humble,
把我扔给法院
dumped my ass in Central Booking,
因为我一个屁都没放
because I ain't say a fucking word to none of them.
那就去告诉他呀
Yeah, so go tell him that shit.
靠 要换了我
Shit, man, if it were me,
就先去找他了
I'd go to him first.
是的 Kev 你知道 先自己招了
Yeah, Kev, you know, definitely jump out in front of that, man,
因为要是等他们找上门来
because if they got to come looking for you,
就让人觉得你有所隐瞒了
it's gonna look like you got something to hide.
- 没错 - 这儿有"Plymouth Rock"
- Definitely. - Got that "Plymouth Rock" over here.
这药很特别哦 买二送一...
Ghetto bird special. Two for one...
你想吃什么
What you want?
菜单 给他张菜单
- Menu, yo. Give him a menu. - Oh.
- 什么好吃 - 我知道才怪
- What's good? - Fuck if I know.
你不能跟顾客顶嘴 混球
You ain't supposed to cuss at the customer, motherfucker.
Kwame
Kwame.
- Darnell - 好吧
- Darnell. - All right.
给我... 披萨
Let me get... pizza.
披萨 要什么喝的吗
Pizza. Anything to drink?
葡萄汽水
Grape soda.
安静
Quiet, please.
- 就这些? - 对
- Is that it? - Yeah.
谢谢 说谢谢
Thank you. Say thank you.
对 谢谢
Yeah. Thank you.
菜单
Menu:
- 他不用说"谢谢"吗 - Darnell
- Don't he got to say "thank you," too? - Darnell.
为什么 本来就该还回来的
What the fuck for? He's supposed to give it back.
因为你对人家有礼貌 人家才会对你好
Because when you are polite to people, they treat you better.
- 坐下 - 能跟你说几句吗
- Have a seat, please. - May I see you?
现在你当服务生 Albert当顾客
Now you try being the waiter, and Albert, be the customer.
- 你想吃什么 - 给我一些蟹饼和可乐
- What you want to eat? - Give me some crab cakes and a coke.
赶紧的
Hurry that shit up, too.
跟第四大道那边通了好几次电话
Been on the phone nonstop with Fourth Avenue.
他们坚持要求每个班都教测试题
They're insisting every class teaches to the test.
老天
Oh, God.
我还以为我们是例外呢
Look. I thought we were the exception.
我是说 这项目的意义就在于此 他们知道的
I mean, that's the point of the project. They know that.
没有例外
No exceptions.
90分钟只上数学和语文
And 90-minute blocks of math or language arts only.
这班的孩子待不上30分钟就得抓狂
This class: Kids can't do 30 minutes without climbing the walls.
听着 我们能不能跟谁谈谈
Look. Isn't there somebody we can sit down and talk with,
- 面对面的? - 事实上 他们跟我说的 第二件事就是这个
- face to face? - Actually, that's the second thing they told me.
学区主管明早想见你们二位
The area superintendent wants to see the two of you tomorrow morning,
九点会议室
9:00 in the conference room.
别恐慌...
Let's not panic...
暂时
yet.
那是谁
跟平时一样
Business as usual.
Marlo
Marlo.
我们劫赌局时你不认识他?
You no know him when we robbed the game?
他没那么倒霉
He ain't that bad a deuce.
我只闻其名
Boy's merely a name to me.
如果你知道是Marlo
If you knew it was Marlo,
还是会去抢的 对吧
you'd still go through with it, no?
我知道就好了 那我会更乐在其中
I wish I'd have known. I'd have enjoyed it that much more.
Bubs
Bubs.
我是Herc 你饿吗
It's Herc. You hungry?
你搞砸了 伙计
Yo, what you done was fucked up, man.
你不知道我听说时有多内疚
You don't know how bad I felt when I heard.
你不止迟到 还直接开过去了
I mean, not only were you late, you just rolled right past.
你没看见我被狠揍吗
Ain't you see me getting beat?
- 我们开过去了? - 我看见你开着警灯驶过去的
- We rolled by? - I seen you with the blue light on, man.
怎样都好 我承认我们的联络出了点问题
Whatever. Look, we had a communication problem, I admit.
我今天给你个电话
But I'm gonna get you a phone today,
这就解决了
and that's gonna solve it for us.
看着吧
You'll see.
事实上 有个摄像头
Thing is, there's this camera--
警局的 几周前失踪了
police department video camera disappeared a few weeks back.
出于某些理由 我没法出面
And for various reasons that I can't get into,
但我得把它弄回来
I got to get it back somehow.
摄像头?
Camera?
可能是个叫Marlo的家伙拿了
Yeah. This fella Marlo probably took it.
- 我不知道他是卖了还是... - 你就为了个摄像头了骚扰我?
- I don't know if he hocked it or if he-- - You're bothering me about a camera?
你本该替我撑腰的 记得吗
You supposed to have my back, remember?
- 你跟我说五分钟就到的 - 我知道 我欠你的
- Five minutes, you told me. - I know. I owe on the deal.
这是Tyrone餐厅的鸡翅
It's Tyrone's, chicken wings.
是这样的
Here's the thing.
我希望你放话出去
I want you to put it out there
说能弄回来的话 有500块奖金
that there's a $500 bounty on this camera if it comes back.
- 不问方式 - 500?
- No questions asked. - 500?
我对天发誓 我保证 只要是那个摄像头
Swear to God. I'm good for it-- if it's the right camera.
这是型号和序列号
Here's the model and serial number.
摄像头给500 鸡翅盒孝敬Bubs 行吗
So it's 500 for the camera and a chicken box for Bubs, huh?
能搞定的话又能多赚100了
It's another 100 to you if this happens.
不过我得尽快拿到摄像头 否则就没戏了
But I need this camera quick, or shit's gonna fly.
听着 伙计
Look, man,
我跟你说过 这不是钱的问题
I told you, it's not about the money for me right now.
懂吗 这混球让我不得安生
All right? This motherfucker, he messing with my livelihood here.
他们老是找我麻烦
They're always coming back, always.
他就像"终结者"什么的
He's like some "Terminator" and shit.
我挺你 我会尽我所能为你排忧解难
I'm with you. I'm gonna do everything I can to help you out with your problem,
你也拉兄弟一把
and you're gonna help me out with mine.
Randy是什么人
Who the fuck is Randy?
附近一个小瘪三
He's a little hopper from around the way.
他不贩毒 但跟Michael一帮混
He ain't in the game, but he be with Michael and them.
他跟警察招了?
And he talking to police?
我知道
I know it.
我知道是他招的 因为我就告诉了他
I know he did, because he was the one I told,
"跟Lex说去后巷 Patrice在等他"
"Go tell Lex to go up to the alley. Patrice is waiting."
- 本来该是你去说的 - 我知道 但这样
- You were supposed to do that. - Yeah, I know, but this way,
我就能跟Lex保持些距离 对吧
try to keep some distance between me and Lex, right?
你跟Randy说了Lex的下场吗
You tell this Randy what happened to Lex?
没有 我发誓
No, I swear it.
滚吧 混球 你还等什么
Go, motherfucker. The fuck you still waiting for?
- 你们他妈的跟着我干嘛 - 放松 小子
- What the fuck y'all following me for? - Easy, son.
不 谁也别跟着我
No. Ain't nobody walking with me nowhere.
拿这个Randy怎么办
What's up with this Randy?
他损害不了我们
He can't hurt us.
- 不过他是个告密者 - 嗯 把这话放出去
- He a snitch, though. - Yeah. Put that around, then.
- Slim - Marlo
- Slim. - Marlo.
- 最近可好 - 没什么可抱怨的
- How you feeling? - Can't complain, yo.
不过快到时候了
Getting to be that time, though.
Joe让我来看看
Joe wanted me to check in, you know?
好吧 拉把椅子过来 我们聊聊吧
All right. Pull up a chair. Let's chop it up.
来了个Barksdale的人
Now, that there a Barksdale boy.
所以呢
So?
这不对劲啊
Don't add up.
不过很有意思
Interesting, though.
买了个即弃手机
Got a burner, see?
有什么情况就给我打电话
If anything else comes up, you call me.
如果那家伙再抢你 要确保东西在他手上
If this guy robs you again, make sure he's holding.
越多越好
The more, the better.
靠 我可没那么多钱
Shit, I ain't got money for all that.
能打四十分钟 我的号码已经存进去了
There's 40 minutes on that, and my number's in there already.
等着吧 今天 最迟明天就会打给你
Watch. I'm gonna call you today or tomorrow at the latest.
一加一
One and one.
靠 小子 他把你整得够呛啊
Damn, son. He did a number on you.
谁啊
Who was it?
Walker警官
Officer Walker.
Walker很邪恶啊
Walker be evil.
- 多少 - 四份
- What up? - Four.
我们得整整他
Yeah, we ought to fuck him up.
- Walker? 他可是警察 - 我就说说
- Walker? Yo, he the police. - I'm just saying.
他说我下次再偷车
He said next time I steal a car,
就死定了
I'm gonna find myself dead.
你会照他说的做吗
You gonna do as he say?
才不
Fuck no.
等我把这些东西取下来 我就满城追着他跑
Soon as I get this shit off, I'll be running his ass all over town.
靠!
Yo, shit!
早告诉你了 Namond
Told you, Namond.
我警告过你 不是吗
Gave you fair warning, didn't l?
- 我什么也没干 - 钱扣下了 抓个现行啊
- I ain't done nothing. - Get the cash. Got you cold.
就你这发型 我在东巴尔的摩也能看见你
Shit, with hair like that, I could make you from East Baltimore.
- 放开我 - 闭嘴!
- Get the fuck off of me, man. - Shut up!
- 看我们找到了什么 - 那些他妈的不是我的!
- Look what I found. - That ain't fucking mine!
双手放在车上!
Hands on the car!
叉开双腿
Spread your legs.
- 我没有... - 闭嘴!
- I ain't fucking got-- - Shut up!
目前为止觉得怎样 好玩吗
How you like it so far? Having fun?
你猜怎样 会更好玩的
Guess what? Gets better.
双手背过来
Give me your hands.
小心头
Watch your head.
靠 你们真会抓紧时间
Damn. Y'all not wasting any time, huh?
我相信凭Nerese的本事
Nerese was good enough to let us
能筹划好议会上的就职典礼
stage in the council suite till the inauguration.
你在大选上的上佳表现 已经让这事板上钉钉了
No doubt after your fine showing in the general.
- 毫无疑问 - 81%?
- No doubt. - 81%?
在一个民主党与共和党数量为九比一的城里
In a city where Democrats outnumber Republicans nine to one--
少于这个数可就难堪了
Anything less would have been an embarrassment.
那么...
So...
我们有什么能为你效劳的 议员?
what can we do for you, Senator?
首先 我想澄清一下
Well, first of all, I wanted to clear the air.
如果初选那事
If there are any hard feelings over what happened
- 给你们照成了什么伤害... - 你要还钱?
- during the primary-- - You gonna give the money back?
议员 我们已经很累了
Senator, it's been a very long day.
我长话短说
I'll cut to the chase.
我知道你对
I understand you have a problem
警局高层有所不满
at the top of the police department.
你要求Burrell辞职 他拒绝了
You asked Burrell to esign. He declined.
我在寻找接替者
I'm looking or a replacement.
部长们都喜欢Burrell
The ministers like Burrell.
议长也是
does the council president.
我们相信等我们找到合适的继任者
We're confident that when we identify a suitable candidate,
Campbell女士和部长们
Ms. Campbell and the ministers
会看见他的领导才能
will see he wisdom of new leadership.
只不过你们得让市议会
Except y'all need to get a pay raise
通过加薪提案
through the city council.
加薪有好处
Pay raise would help.
我能让Nerese通过加薪的提案
I can ask Nerese about that pay raise getting passed,
也许还能说服几位部长
maybe convince some of the ministers
他们该撇开Burrell向前看了
they need to move on from Burrell.
这情况
Situation would have to be resolved
越早解决越好
sooner rather than later.
我尽量 搭档
Do my best, partner.
为此我们该如何回报你呢
And what do we do for you in return?
我要去安纳波利斯
I'm in Annapolis.
听说你几年内也会去(即参选州长)
Word I'm hearing, you may be there too, in a couple of years.
到时我们可能会在一起合作无间
We may find ourselves working together closely.
感谢你们抽时间见我
Thanks for your time.
老天啊
Jesus Christ.
他是个老油条
He's slick.
为短线的骗局道歉
Apologizes for the short con,
接着就给我们下了个长线的套
and then in the next breath setting us up for the long.
他和Burrell好比两个贼
He and Burrell are as thick as thieves.
我们知道这长线骗局是什么吗
And do we know what the long con is?
至少我们知道他在搞阴谋诡计
At least we know he's running one.
科奥奥奥...
Shiiiii...
再打
Try calling again.
伙计 我知道她不会接的
Man, I know she not gonna answer.
我妈去大西洋城时从不接电话
My moms don't answer when she go to A.C.
她什么时候回来
When she coming back?
她之后会去纽约
She going to New York after.
她上纽约干嘛
What's she doing in New York?
购物
Shopping.
去看表演 "紫色"
Going to see some show, "The Color Purple."
我的工作好玩就在这了
See, now this is where my job gets good.
你该联系你监护人
You could reach a guardian, we both know
未成年人监管人会在 你第一次因贩毒被捕时做记录
the juvenile master's gonna recog you on a first-time drug arrest.
但现在你最好带了牙刷了 孩子
But now you'd better have a toothbrush on you, son,
你今晚得进未成年人拘留中心了
because it's gonna be baby booking tonight.
Namond 你怕了?
Namond, you scared?
如果是Cheltenham 我还可以理解
I mean, if it was Cheltenham, I don't blame you,
但未成年人拘留中心就在城另一边
but baby booking's just across town.
那里东区的人跟西区的有冲突
The East Side be beefing with the West Side in there.
那里有人被强奸什么的
There's some dudes be getting raped and shit.
我听来是这样的
I mean, that's what I be hearing.
那里是很糟 不过不确定有没有那么糟
It's bad in there. I don't know if it's that bad.
我听来的不一样
Well, I hear different.
你没其他家人了吗
You got no other family?
我在P.G.郡有个阿姨
I got a aunt down in P.G. County.
有号码吗
You got a number?
- 这么晚了 我可不想载你过去 所以... - 拜托 伙计
- Well, I ain't driving you this late, anyway, so-- - Come on, man.
我告诉你怎么办
Tell you what:
我们两个兄弟上双班
two of my guys are working a double,
今晚值夜班
working midnight shift tonight.
如果你能安安稳稳地坐在那边的长椅上
If you can plant yourself on that bench over there,
你就能在这待一晚
you can stay here for the night.
但明天一早你就得给你阿姨打电话
But first thing tomorrow, you got to raise that aunt
或打给你妈 否则我只好移送你
or raise your moms, or I got to process you.
别离开长椅
You don't move off that bench.
要上厕所 就马上去
You need the bathroom, you go now.
否则就给我安安稳稳地坐着
Otherwise, just... sit tight,
别给谁惹麻烦  否则他们会把你移送到那边
don't give anybody any trouble, or they'll process you right then and there.
不用了 谢了
I'm cool. Thanks.
我真他妈太有爱了
Fucking charity ward here.
我去跟值班负责人说一声
I'll go tell the shift commander.
警督...
Yo, Lieutenant...
他是警察?
He a 50:
不是 也许只是替我妈保管着
No. Probably copping it for my moms.
就为这个?
That's why?
听着 我跟你们说了
Look. I told y'all,
我只想让他消失
I just want him gone.
只想让他远离我和Bug
I just want him away from me and Bug.
他对你做了什么
The fuck he do to you?
好吧
All right.
我们会处理的 老板
We'll take care of it, boss.
昨晚二区又发生了一起教堂窃案
Another church burglary in sector two last night.
- Madison公园卫理公会教 - 这大概就是你所谓的疹子
- Madison Park Methodist. - This would be what you'd call a rash.
而我们得擦些药膏
And we could use some ointment.
我们得逮住这些混球
We need to arrest these fucks.
- 有什么线索了吗 - 还没
- We getting anywhere on that? - Not yet.
上次是谁逮的人? McNulty?
Who caught the last one? McNulty?
在处理呢
Working it.
- 我们等会谈一谈 - 好的
- We should talk. - All right.
说到逮捕 上头放话说要扫荡街角
Speaking of arrests, word from on high is to sweep corners.
他们下个月要逮两倍的人
They want arrests to double over the next month.
- 他妈的怎么做 - 老天 我还以为竞选结束了呢
- How the fuck how: - Jesus, I thought the election was over.
老大们想抓破换生活质量的人
Bosses want quality-of-life violations.
什么意思 警督 游荡罪吗
What are we talking about, Lieutenant, loitering?
- 滋事 公共场所猥亵 - 胡说八道
- Disorderlies, public indecency. - Oh, this is horseshit.
- 破窗理论 - 在纽约有用
- Broken-windows theory. - Worked in New York.
破窗理论:纽约警方曾利用此理论整治地铁犯罪  主要观点为小奸小恶是暴力犯罪的温床
- 怕你不知道 这可不是纽约 - 但也许有效
- Case you ain't noticed, this ain't New York. - But it could work here.
- 才怪 - 从没被正确执行过
- Never has. - Never been done right.
还有酗酒
Open containers, too.
- 开罚单不行吗 - 得做得更多
- What's wrong with writing a ticket? - More of that, too.
局长想要增加逮捕数量
The word is, the commissioner himself wants to juke arrests.
杯中物本来在这城里是神圣不可侵犯的
Open container used to be sacrosanct in this town.
当它还在纸袋里就是了 (指禁酒时将酒瓶用纸袋套着饮用)
Long as it was in a paper bag.
他们充分尊重这点
They gave you that much respect.
男人想喝什么是他自己的事
Man's beverage was his business.
你带他们去餐厅?
You took them to a restaurant?
- 对 Ruth Chris - 亚麻餐巾
- Yeah. Ruth Chris. - Linen napkins.
嗯 银餐具 不止一把叉子
Yeah. Silverware, more than one fork.
- 他们表现如何 - 对他们来说算相当好了
- How'd they do? - Eh, pretty well, considering.
他们让我们难堪了吗
Did they embarrass us?
我们? 没有...
Us? No, uh...
我们没关系 不过...
we're fine with it, but, uh...
我是说 他们害怕 窘迫
I mean, they were intimidated, embarrassed,
相当尴尬 但他们挺过去了
and awkward as hell, but they made it through.
Shepherdson女士 这些孩子
Ms. Shepherdson, these aren't the kids
不可能安坐着进行州测验
that are gonna be able to sit still for the statewide tests,
更别提考出好成绩了
much less do well on them.
这些孩子还会
These were the kids that were gonna make it impossible
- 影响其他的孩子 - 所以我们把他们除名?
- for anyone else to do well. - So we're writing them off?
不 我们不这么干
No, that's what we're not doing.
你们不是在教育他们 是在教他们社交
You're not educating them. You're socializing them.
他们之前也没在受教育啊 别那么冥顽不灵
They weren't being educated before. There's no point in being obtuse.
- 你说什么 - 打住 打住
- Excuse me: - Hold on. Hold on.
听着 他想说的是
Look. What he's saying is this:
你把教科书放在这些孩子面前
I mean, you put a textbook in front of these kids,
在黑板上写下问题
put a problem on a blackboard,
或教他们州测验上的题目 这些都不重要
or teach them every problem on some statewide test, it won't matter,
无关紧要
none of it,
因为他们不是从我们的世界学东西 是从他们的世界里学东西
because they're not learning for our world, they're learning for theirs.
他们明确地知道自己要学什么
And they know exactly what it is they're training for
每个人期望他们成为怎样的人
and what it is everyone expects them to be.
我期望他们当好学生
I expect them to be students.
但这无关你我
But it's not about you or us,
或测验 体系
or the tests or the system.
主要是他们的自我期望
It's what they expect of themselves.
我是说 他们每一个人 都知道自己会回到街角
I mean, every single one of them know they headed back to the corners.
他们的兄弟姐妹 妈的 还有他们的父母...
Their brothers and sisters-- shit, their parents--
他们也经历过同样的课堂 不是吗
they came through these same classrooms, didn't they?
我们假装教育他们 他们假装学习
We pretended to teach them, they pretended to learn,
结果怎样呢
and where-- where'd they end up?
还不是在街角
Same damn corners.
我是说 这些孩子不是傻瓜
I mean, they're not fools, these kids.
他们不了解我们的世界 但他们了解自己的世界
They don't know our world, but they know their own.
我的意思是 老天 他们...
I mean, Jesus, they--
他们看透我们了
they see right through us.
我想你批准这项目时我们已经说清楚了
I think we made that clear when you approved the project.
- 暂时的批准 - 你暂时地批准这项目时
- Provisionally approved. - When you provisionally approved the project,
我们就明确了要教这些孩子
we made it clear that we would be addressing children
必要的社交技能
that required socialization
- 之后才能被适当地教育 - 我们不能撒谎
- before they could be properly educated. - We can't lie.
对他们不能
Not to them.
警监 3号线
Captain, line three.
点名结束了
Roll call's over.
联系上你妈了没
You get a line on your mother yet?
操蛋的疏于监管啊
Fucking neglect case here, I want it.
你那阿姨呢
How about that aunt:
就没哪个你认识的人了吗 没哪个有责任感的成年人?
Ain't nobody else you know? No other responsible adult?
- 比如谁 - 不知道
- Like who: - I don't know.
我只是给你最后一次机会
I'm just trying to give you one last shot here
因为一旦我今天走出这个门
because once I go on the street today,
你就得去未成年人拘留中心了
you're gonna have to go to booking.
我有个老师
I got a teacher.
Colvin先生 你认识他吗
Mr. Colvin. You know him?
他以前是警察
He used to be police.
高个 光头?
tall, Bald:
嗯
Yeah.
认识
Yeah, I know him.
你让那个告密的来怎么样
What if you get the one snitch?
那个推着手推车的 什么名字来着
The one with the cart. What's his name?
Bubbles
Bubbles.
Bubbles 对
Bubbles. Yeah.
你让Bubbles说他就是Fuzzy Dunlop
You get Bubbles to say he's Fuzzy Dunlop.
不过Bubbles多年前就是注册的线人了
Except Bubbles has been a registered Cl for years.
Kima还是便衣时给了他一个编号
Kima gave him a number back when she was in plainclothes, man.
还有 Herc 你跟他合作 使的是Barksdale案的编号
And, Herc, you worked with him under that number on the Barksdale stuff.
你想怎么在身份上蒙混过去
So how would you fuck up the lD?
操蛋
Fuck me, man.
听着 要了结这破事 唯一的方法
Look. The only way to get out from under this
就是别再撒谎了 懂吗
is to stop fucking lying, okay
带点种
You grab your dick,
走进Marimow的办公室 跟他说
you walk into Marimow's office, and you say,
"警督 我犯了个错"
"Lieutenant, I made a mistake.
"我把我的情报来源归于一个线人"
"l attributed my PC to an informant
"其实是我通过摄像头看来的"
when in fact I had it off a camera."
告诉他我没通过书面渠道 拿了证物科的摄像头
That I got from lSD without going through the proper channels.
不行 不行  为这个他会拿走我警衔上的杠杠
No no no. He's gonna take my stripes on this.
也许吧
Maybe he does,
但如果你等到证物科来找摄像头
but if you wait until lSD comes looking for that camera
然后他发现你对他撒了谎
and he figures out the lie for himself,
他会拿走你的蛋蛋
he takes your fucking balls.
快点!
Come on!
走吧!
Let's go!
绕过街角
Around the corner.
逮到你了 混球
Got you now, motherfucker.
我查了一下我的报告
In going over some of my paperwork,
也许是我疏忽了
it occurs to me I may have been neglectful.
看看这些垃圾!
Look at all this crap!
每一天
Every day,
越来越多Lester Freamon 惹来的狗屁来烦我们
more and more of Lester Freamon's bullshit washes up with us.
你他妈说的什么
What the fuck are you saying?
我的报告可能有点草率
That my paperwork may have been a little sloppy,
结果
and as a result,
我有些东西给混淆了
I confused myself on some things.
没错 你是够草率的
No shit, you were sloppy.
其实我查看了几周来你的工作记录
I actually went back a couple weeks on your run sheets.
没见过哪里有说跟线人238会面的
Nothing there references a meet with a Cl 238.
你看了我所有的工作记录?
You went through all my run sheets?
看得相当仔细
The best I could.
- 长官 听我说... - 不管是谁 给我关了
- Sir, listen-- - I don't care who it is. Turn that fucking thing off.
我开始相信
I am starting to believe
这个Fuzzy
that this Fuzzy fella
压根不存在
doesn't exist.
我开始相信
I am starting to believe
你只是跟踪Stanfield进了火车站
that you just followed Stanfield into the train station
抓了他头一个碰上的女人
and grabbed the first broad he brushed up against.
- 是这样吗 - 不 不是 长官
- That what happened? - No. No, sir.
你要敢骗我 警司
You lie to me now, Sergeant,
我保证有你好看
and I guaran-fucking-tee you I will jam you up,
把这烂摊子送到内部调查处
ship this whole mess to llD
把文件夹到你的报告里
and be there to pass out sandwiches at your execution.
- 是 长官 - 你还没给我个
- Yes, sir. - You haven't brought me a case
值得一提的案子
yet worth talking about,
不论是Marlo Stanfield 还是其他人的
not on Marlo Stanfield, not on anyone.
你给我些内部调查处的投诉之外的东西
You bring me something other than llD complaints,
我也许还有理由替你解决些麻烦
and I might have some reason to let a few things slide.
生我气
Mad at me:
- 拜托啊 - Dukie见谁都不爽
- Come on, now. - Dukie's just mad at everybody.
告密的贱货
Snitch bitch.
什么情况
Yo, what the fuck was that?
不知道
I don't know.
不敢相信你们会这么做
I can't believe y'all are doing this shit.
你们使社区的生活质量降低了
You're degrading the quality of life in this neighborhood.
- 麦芽酒 - 拜托 伙计!
- Malt liquor. - Oh, come on, man!
哥们 你该见识见识皮尔森啤酒
Brother, you got to shake hands with a pilsner,
- 或者美味的啤酒 - 靠 干嘛!
- maybe a nice tail ale. - Hell, what-- oh, man!
我的饮料! 我的鞋!
My brew! My shoes!
- 老天! 伙计 - 犯什么事了
- God! Man. - What's the violation?
占用巴士站车位 注册过期
Parking in a bus stop, expired registration.
头等的警务工作啊 Baker
First-class police work, Baker.
上面发话了
Yeah, well, this is the word from up on high,
市局八楼的声音
straight from the eighth floor downtown.
敬爱的老大们要为新政府刷数据
Blessed bosses juking stats for the new administration.
我知道你觉得这很扯淡
I know you think it's bullshit,
但他们让我干什么 我就干什么
but I spend my shift where they tell me.
Baker 告诉你个小秘密
Baker, let me tell you a little secret:
将在外
A patrolling officer on his beat
君命有所不受
is the one true dictatorship in America.
我们可以凭直觉抓人
We can lock a guy up on a humble;
我们可以真的抓人 也可以说 去他的
we can lock him up for real; or we can say, fuck it--
把车停在高速路边 一醉方休
pull under the expressway and drink ourselves to death,
我们的搭档会给我们打掩护
and our side partners will cover it.
这样就没人 我是说 没人
So no one-- and I mean no one--
能告诉我们怎样虚度我们的工作时间
tells us how to waste our shift.
我把教堂窃案的报告拿出来了
Pulled the reports on those church burglaries.
- 是吗 - 对 有点固定的模式
- Yeah? - Yeah. There's a pattern.
时间和地点
Times and locations.
他们经由Sandtown-Winchester 由西向西北作案
They're working west by northwest through Sandtown-Winchester.
最近三起 这儿 这儿 还有这儿
The last three-- here, here, and here--
这些涂成蓝色的是他们还没光顾过的教堂
these ones in blue are the churches they haven't hit
离他们光顾过的最近的几所
closest to the ones they have.
- 你从事发报告上看出那么多? - 我们做报告不就为了这个吗
- You got all this from the incident reports? - That's why we do the paperwork.
给我他妈的开罚单?
Giving me a motherfucking ticket, man?
你他妈有病啊?
Are you out of your motherfucking mind?
我住这儿的 伙计!
I live here, man!
可能要失控啊
This could get out of hand.
这不就是我们想要的吗 逮捕更多人?
That's what we want, isn't it? More arrests?
走吧
Come on.
没有公平 就没有和平
No justice, no peace.
就今晚
It'll only be for tonight.
他妈明天从纽约回来
Mama gets back from New York tomorrow.
你决定吧
Your call.
小伙似乎对你欣赏有加啊 老大
The young man seems to think highly of you, boss.
他带着敬意提起你的名字
He invoked your name with a measure of respect.
几周前
It wasn't but a few weeks ago
我跟他在教室里 他除了神之儿女什么称呼都用上了
I was in a room with him being called everything but a child of God.
"Colvin先生"
"Mr. Colvin, sir.
"去你妈的"
Fuck you."
是啊 不过至少我说了"先生"
Yeah, well, at least I said, "Mr."
- 什么指控 - 贩毒
- So what was the charge? - Slinging.
他在外面混了几周了
He'd been out there a few weeks or so.
第一次抓他 算是第二次警告
First pop, second warning from me.
也许你该把他送上少管所的巴士
Maybe you should put him on the juvenile bus.
他那么想当帮派分子
He wants so bad to be a gangster,
也许是时候让他感受一下铁窗生涯了
maybe it's time he get a taste of what a real lockup's all about, you know?
拜托 C先生 别那样对我
Come on, Mr. C., don't do me like that.
昨晚我让他在缉毒组的长椅上睡了一夜
I made him sleep on the DEU bench last night,
算是解恨了吗
if that counts for anything.
没别人了吗
Isn't there anybody else?
朋友 亲戚什么的
Friend, relative, anybody?
你对白痴一向很好 老大
You've always been good with the knuckleheads, boss.
好吧 我给我妻子打个电话
Ahh. All right. Let me go call my wife.
到那栋楼上去
Yeah. Go up in that building.
这太美味了
Mmm, man, that was delicious.
还有呢
There's more.
不用了 女士 留着肚子吃水果馅饼
Uh, no, ma'am. Saving room for the cobbler.
- 冰激凌? - 啊?
- A la mode? - Huh
要在上面加冰淇淋吗
Would you like ice cream on it?
哦 要的 女士
Oh! Oh, yes, ma'am.
很有礼貌
Nice manners.
根据你电话里跟我说的 Bunny
From what you told me on the phone, Bunny,
我还以为会出点小岔子呢
I was expecting more of an adventure.
- Bunny? - 我朋友叫我Bunny
- Bunny? - Only my friends call me Bunny.
- 为什么 - 你不用知道
- Yeah, but why? - You don't need to know.
如果你敢告诉被人 我会扯烂你蛋蛋
And if you tell anybody, I'll cut your balls off.
扯烂他们 放到罐子里送给Donnelly
I'll cut them off, give 'em to Donnelly in a jar.
别怀疑 小子
Don't doubt me, boy.
你们没孩子?
You ain't got no kids?
长大了 在大学里 或毕业了
Grown. They're at college and past that.
你跟我说这些孩子很粗鲁
You told me these kids were rough.
谢谢 亲爱的 别被骗了
Thank you, sweetie. But don't be fooled.
这是他Eddie Haskell的演技 (一情景喜剧中的小孩角色)
This is his Eddie Haskell act.
Eddie Haskell? 谁啊
Eddie Haskell? Who that?
就是你啊 小子 相信我
You are, son. Trust me.
坐
Take a seat.
把他跟其他人一样让他对墙站着
Put yours against the wall with the others.
欢迎马车就要从未成年人拘留中心回来了
Welcome wagon's on their way back from booking.
- 我们要审讯室的钥匙 - 为什么
- We need the key to the interview room. - What the fuck for?
入室行窃重罪
Felony burglary.
重罪?
Felony?
他们从Fulton街的St. Martin教堂出来 被我们逮个正着
Caught them coming out of St. Martin's on Fulton.
用那个指控
Charging them with the one,
但可能还能审出一些来
but we might work back on a few more.
不是吧
No shit:
我就知道巴尔的摩还是有真正的犯罪的
Fucking knew there was still some real criminals left in Baltimore.
对天发誓 我还看见了横穿马路的罪名
Swear to God, I'm seeing citations for jaywalking.
我们因为人们喝酒
We're locking people up for open container,
扰乱秩序 闲荡而逮捕他们
for disorderly, for loitering.
社区里的人会满意这种 为提高生活质量做的逮捕
The neighborhood people, sometimes they appreciate quality-of-life arrests.
只不过我们都抓到社区里的人头上了
Except we're locking up the neighborhood people.
我的几个弟兄 眼里只有数据
Some of my guys, all they see are the stats.
我是说 竞选他妈的结束了不是吗
I mean, the election's fucking over, right?
我们做这些干嘛
Who are we doing this for?
这是Burrell还是Rawls下的命令?
Is this coming from Burrell or Rawls?
我们是从巡逻总指挥处接到的命令
We got it from the chief of patrol.
这纯属瞎指挥
It's rolling downhill, for sure.
- 士气如何 - 一半一半吧
- Morale: - Split down the middle, I'd say.
喜欢数据的警员乐开了怀
The officers that love the stat are jazzed.
其他的呢
The rest of them:
我们不知道何去何从
We don't know where to turn.
我以为换了市长会不一样了
I thought a new hump as mayor might change this shit,
而不是更差
not ramp it up.
你还在睡那个婊子?
Hey, you still fucking that bitch?
嗯 痛死了 伙计
Yeah. It burning like hell, man.
你什么时候让那婊子也痛一下? 看看
When you gonna burn the bitch back? Oh, check it.
- Slim - B
- Slim. - B.
- 怎么样 - 还行
- What up. - All right.
- Poot - 不错
- Poot. - It's good.
- 听说你出来了 - 嗯
- Heard you're out. - Yeah.
- 欢迎回来 - 谢了 伙计
- Welcome home. - Thanks, dawg.
你跟了Prop Joe了
And you with Prop Joe now.
想不到啊
Never would have thought.
世事无常啊
Yeah, well, life's strange.
是啊 操蛋
Yeah. Holler.
Bodie... 你跟Marlo怎样了
Bodie... how you and Marlo?
跟他没什么冲突吧
You okay with him?
据我所知没有 干嘛
As far as I know, yeah. Why?
他对你哥们做的事
What he did to your boy.
你说的是谁
What boy are you talking?
大个儿
Big boy,
整天拿手擦这里的家伙
the one rub his hands together all the time?
Kevin? 他怎么了
Kevin? What about him?
你没听说?
You ain't heard?
Chris和Snoop带着他到了后巷
Chris and Snoop walked him down an alley.
现在大概横尸了
He in a vacant now.
你怎么知道的
How you know that?
我看见他们对他下手的
I seen them lay hands on the boy.
现在已经传开了
And now the word out on the street.
很遗憾 哥们
Sorry, dawg.
开车
Let's roll.
Plymouth Rock 这里有Plymouth Rock
Plymouth Rock. Got that Plymouth Rock.
好了
All right.
现在看20页的例题
But now look at the next example question on page 20.
你们可以看到...
As you can see...
如果你们呢翻到20页
if you turn to page 20,
他们会问你们
they will sometimes ask you for words
有下划线的词的反义词
that are the opposite of words that are underlined.
- 谢谢 Pryzbylewski先生 - 谢谢
- Uh, thank you, Mr. Pryzbylewski. - Thank you.
好了 把你们的教科书放一边
All right, put away your test notebooks.
明天再学
Work on those tomorrow.
我们还有45分钟课
We have, uh, 45 minutes left.
我们可以看"最后的莫西干人"...
We can do "Last of the Mohicans"--
- 不要! - 不要!
- No! - No!
- 也可以练习概率 - 好
- Or practice probabilities. - Yes.
- 我去取道具 Prezbo先生 - 好的
- I'll get the stuff, Mr. Prezbo. - All right.
我想看到大家把工作表都放一边
And I want to see everybody's worksheets out.
- Kareem 你要跟我玩骰子吗 - 不要
- Hey, Kareem, you want to play dice with me? - Not with you.
我们不但是在玩游戏
And we're not just playing games here.
- 我们是在练习数学 - 我跟你玩
- We're doing math. - I'll roll with you, man.
- 来吧 - 真的
- Come on. - No kidding.
来吧
We are.
我们的小伙要睡觉了 看见没
That's my boy resting his head, see?
嗯
Mmm.
Renaldo 想吃吗
Hey, Renaldo, you want one?
- 不要 - 是Faidley店的哦
- No. - They're from Faidley's, yo.
他可能会在家待一整天 知道吗
He might stay home all day, you know?
我们得弄清楚 不是吗
We gonna find out, ain't we?
- 我要看我的社保号 - 你有预约吗
- Like to see about my DSS code. - Do you have an appointment?
- 我为什么要预约 - Zenobia 她不用预约
- Why I need an appointment? - Zenobia, I don't think she needs an appointment.
抱歉 我只是想演得真实点
Sorry, just trying to make it realistic.
那我能见谁了吗
So I get to see somebody?
你要取个号等着
You're gonna have to take a number and wait.
我现在就要见上负责人
I need to see somebody right now.
别生气 生气于事无补
Don't get angry. Anger doesn't help.
只会引起别人的防御心理
It just makes people defensive.
冷静地告诉她你的要求
Tell her what you need calmly.
- 卡这个月没到 - 我们寄过去了
- Card didn't come this month. - We mailed it.
- 也许被盗了 - 抱歉 我们爱莫能助
- Maybe it got stolen. - Heh. Sorry. Nothing we can do.
- 操你 - Chandra!
- Fuck you. - Chandra!
- 她不肯帮我 - 他们就是这么办事的
- She ain't helping me. - That's how they do.
你只要告诉她你的要求
Just tell her what you need.
- 我要再办一张卡 贱货 - Chandra
- Need another card, bitch. - Chandra.
这就真实了
And that's reality.
去你妈的
Fuck you for real.
冷静 冷静 跟Mason女士出去
Calm down. Calm down. Go with Ms. Mason.
- 放开你的手 - Mason女士!
- Get your hands off! - Ms. Mason!
我去叫学校保安
I'll get the school police.
她就像...
She was like...
- 接着 接着 接着她就像... - 典型的一天?
- And then-- and then-- and then she was like... - Typical day?
不知道 我第一次来
I wouldn't know. My first time.
你第一次来?
Your first time?
Donnelly女士监管这个项目
Mrs. Donnelly oversees this project.
好吧
Okay.
早上好 女士们
Good morning, ladies.
帮个忙 让我挣点吃的好吗
Help a man get something to eat?
上帝保佑你
God bless.
早上好 牧师先生
Good morning, Reverend.
喂
Yo.
- 很高兴你总算回电话了 - 昨天我在开会
- Glad you finally answered. - Yeah, I was in a meeting yesterday.
你盯上那混蛋了?
You got the asshole pinned down?
没有 我发现了Marlo的人 正要送货
Nah, I got Marlo's people-- getting ready to make a drop.
- 在哪 - Edmondson 靠近Pulaski
- Where? - Edmondson, near Pulaski.
你现在盯着他们?
You eyeballing them right now?
嗯 他取到货了 黑包 放在后备箱里
Yeah, he got the package. Black bag, putting it in the trunk.
- 上车了 - 什么车
- He getting in right now. - What make?
最新的林肯
Late model Lincoln.
- 要车牌号吗 - 说
- You want the license? - Yeah, give it.
P R 8 Z G O D
P-R-8-Z-G-O-D.
他开车了 转上Gilmore去了
Yeah. Yeah, he pulling out now, turning down Gilmore.
Dozerman 给我接F队 干得好 Bubs 我们去追
Dozerman, get me Foxtrot. Good job, Bubs. We're on it.
女士 手机要吗 还能打大约半小时
Ladies, a cell phone? It's got, like, a half hour on it.
不 谢了
No thank you.
我今天所见
What I saw today
不是我所知道的教育
wasn't education as I understand the term,
他们也没学到什么社交
and they didn't seem very socialized, either.
你没碰上情况好的时候
You didn't catch us on our best day.
- 也没碰上情况最糟的时候吧 - 总的说了 他们进步很多了
- Or your worst day? - On the whole, they've actually made a lot of progress.
他们来到这个班
Look, I mean, they come to class,
他们学得更多 我们有在帮到他们
they're more engaged. We're reaching them.
打架或逃课也更少
Fewer outbursts, no suspensions.
但他们真能学到东西吗
But are they really learning anything?
- 是的 我相信他们能学到 - 说真的吧
- Yes. We believe they are. - Be truthful.
如果这个项目
If this program were to continue
还要在这一学年继续下去
through the rest of the school year,
你们的学生中有多少
how many of your students could realistically
能回到普通班?
be expected to return to a regular classroom?
你怎么想 Duquette女士?
What do you think, Ms. Duquette?
Namond Darnell 也许还有Zenobia
Namond, Darnell, maybe Zenobia.
听着 考虑到我们的起点
Yeah, look. I mean, considering where we started
考虑到那些孩子没把 其他的班级闹得天翻地覆
and considering that those kids ain't out there tearing up other classes--
好吧 Donnelly女士
Okay. Mrs. Donnelly.
惊人的成就
A tremendous achievement.
Withers先生
Mr. Withers:
我赞成Donnelly女士的意见
I'll go along with Mrs. Donnelly.
你还没发表意见
You haven't said anything yet.
我想不出有什么好处
I just don't see it.
这些孩子很多都无可救药了
Many of these kids are profoundly damaged--
他们所见所闻 他们的生活方式
what they've seen, how they've lived.
我认为目前所取得的进步都是暂时的
And I think any gain or progress is temporary.
我认为这个项目是有缺陷的
I think this project may be flawed.
F 23-30 发现嫌疑人
Foxtrot 23-30. We have a visual on the suspect.
嫌疑车辆在Mulberry向东行驶 收到吗
Vehicle headed east on Mulberry. Do you copy?
- 收到 我们就快到了 - 收到
- 10-4. We're almost there. - 10-4.
接到你电话后
After your phone call,
我查了 命令是Burrell直接下达的
I checked. It came directly from Burrell.
绕过了Rawls 我特别叮嘱他...
He bypassed Rawls after l specifically told him he was--
Burrell出招了
Burrell's making a play
为了让你留下他
for you to keep him.
就靠... 你怎么说来着
By, uh, just-- what did you call that?
- 刷数据 - 难以置信
- Juking the stats. - Guy is unbelievable.
这跟我跟Rawls谈的完全背道而驰
It runs completely counter to all my discussions with Rawls,
还有你和其他人
with you, with everyone.
他也是发出警告
He's also serving notice.
展示他对警局的掌控
He's reasserting control of the department.
他可能觉得你炒不了他就是炒不了他
He probably figures if you can't fire him, then you can't fire him.
Rawls知道吗
And does Rawls know?
我猜Rawls几天前就知道了
My guess is, Rawls heard about it days ago
从几个区警长处得知
from half a dozen district commanders.
他干嘛不来找我
Why wouldn't he come to me?
跟他谈谈吧
Talk to him.
为什么你又来找我 我是说 干嘛不找Rawls?
Why did you come to me? I mean, why not go to Rawls?
因为我要知道你是不是认真的
Because I need to know if you're serious.
如果Rawls已经找过你 而这破事还是在继续
If Rawls already came to you and this shit is still going on,
那就是你没意见了 这对我就成问题了
then you're okay with it, which is for me a problem.
如果他没找你
If he didn't come to you,
那就是他没意见 那也成问题了
then either he's okay with it, which is also a problem,
又或者他撒手不管 让Burrell作茧自缚
or he's letting it go, trying give Burrell enough rope
好让你因他不听话炒了他
for you to get angry and fire the man for insubordination.
但我要知道你的立场
But I need to know where you stand.
我向你保证过
Well, I gave you my word.
是的 你保证过
Yes. You did.
谢谢你能够越级找我
Well, thanks for going outside the chain of command.
别期待我习惯成自然
Don't expect me to make a habit of it.
待在车上!
Stay in the car!
待在车上 手放在方向盘上
Stay in the car. Keep your hands on the wheel.
- 让我们看见你的手 - 发生什么事了 警官
- Let's see those hands. - What's the problem, Officer?
慢慢从车里走出来 举起双手
Step slowly out of the vehicle. Keep your hands up.
- 孩子 轻点 - 闭上你鸟嘴 我不是你孩子
- Son, be gentler than that. - Shut the fuck up. I ain't your son.
看好这家伙...
This guy...
是什么 什么
What's this, huh? What's this?
你知道吗
Do you know what?
我很确定我要你的名字和警徽号
I'm gonna damn sure get your name and badge number.
Daniels 我不认识
Daniels. I don't think I know him.
他没玩过多少政治
Oh, he hasn't played much politics,
不过他曾跟11区的新议员有过婚姻
though he used to be married to the new councilwoman in the 11th.
- Marla Daniels? - 就是她
- Marla Daniels? - Mm-hmm. That's the one.
我们最不想看到的就是他当局长 Nerese
This is the last man we want as police commissioner, Nerese.
我几年前跟他对上过
I mean, I squared off against this fellow a few years back,
他根本不听我的
and he wouldn't listen to me.
他也不会听你或部长们的
He's not gonna listen to you or the ministers
或社区里的其他人
or anyone else in the community.
- 只听Carcetti的? - 嗯哼
- Just Carcetti? - Mm-hmm.
他是市长的嫡系 肯定的
Oh, he's the mayor's boy, definitely.
Carcetti想涨薪多少
Carcetti is looking for how much of a salary bump?
至少5万 好让这职位 在全国范围内有竞争力
50,000, at least, to make the position competitive nationally.
给他2万5
Give him 25.
这会让他认为他最终把你争取过来了
It'll be enough to make him think he'll win you over eventually
但又不够他吸引真正的人才
but less than he needs to entice anyone real.
同时 Carcetti提升Daniels前
Meanwhile, Carcetti's gonna have to give Daniels
会让他在刑事调查部门待上6个月
six months in ClD before he can bump him again,
做足门面
for appearance's sake.
我们就能争取到时间了
So we're buying time here.
足够Ervin向市长表明他才堪大用
Enough for Ervin to show the new mayor who butters the bread.
也能除去Cedric Daniels头上的光环
And for events to take the new-penny shine off Cedric Daniels.
我恰好知道他不是他所假装的那种圣人
I happen to know he's less the saint than he pretends to be.
我是Davis参议员
This is Senator Davis.
市长在吗
Is the Mayor in at the moment?
告诉他 他的朋友Clay
Well...you just tell him his friend Clay
让议长通过了给警察局长
got the council president to un-ass a salary bump
涨薪的提案
for the police commissioner.
告诉他...
You tell him...
写下来
write this down, now.
告诉他
You tell him
Davis议员一切以他的利益为重
that Senator Davis has his interests at heart.
对
Right.
谢谢
Thanks.
妈 纽约怎么样
Hey, Ma. How was New York?
Brice女士 你好
Hey, Ms. Brice. How are you?
你哪位
Who asking?
他是我老师 妈 Colvin先生
This is my teacher, Mom-- Mr. Colvin.
他来这干嘛
Why he here?
你惹事了?
You in trouble?
他昨晚住在我那儿
He stayed at our house last night,
当你在纽约的时候
with you being in New York and all.
告诉她
Tell her.
条子把我抓了 说我贩毒
The cops picked me up, saying I was slinging.
他们原来要把我送到未成年人拘留中心
They was gonna send me to baby booking.
但我们带他回家
But we took him in.
你他妈的离我儿子远一点
You leave my son the fuck alone.
而你 你怕进未成年人拘留中心?
And you, you afraid to go to baby booking?
你他妈什么毛病 小鬼 滚回屋里去!
The fuck is wrong with you, boy? Get in the damn house!
孩子们说得有道理
Kid got the point.
这些醉酒啊 闹事啊 打手枪的小鬼
all these drunk and disorderlies and squeegee boys,
涂鸦艺术家 公众场合随地小便者
graffiti artists, and public urinators,
现在还有两项盗窃罪
and here we come in with a pair of felony burglaries.
你给他套上项圈真是好人啊
Nice of you to give him the collar.
他可能会成为一个正派的警察
Well, he might turn out a decent police.
年轻一代总得有人做警察
- Got to come from somewhere. Young generation. - Uh-huh.
你们呢
What about you guys?
要追随你们老爸的足迹吗
You gonna follow in your dad's footsteps?
才不呢
Hello, I don't think so.
不要
Not.
- 那做什么 - 电子游戏设计
- What, then? - Video game designer.
摇滚明星
- Rock star. - Ahh.
他们想挣钱
Ah, they want to make money.
- 你把他们教得很好 - 你呢 小Bunk?
- You schooled them well. - How about you, Little Bunk?
你会像你爸那样当个侦探吗
You'll be a detective like your daddy?
警察头子
- Chief of police. - Nah.
干嘛不呢 你呢
Why not? How about you?
他还处在 你知道
Oh, he's still in that, you know,
怕生的阶段
pediatric neurosurgeon stage.
Elena 你好吗
Hey! Elena, how are you doing?
好着呢 你呢
I'm good. How are you?
还行吧
Can't complain.
孩子们 你们好吗
Hey, boys. How are you?
你们能打个招呼吗
Can you say hi?
听着 他们很好
Listen. They're fine.
他们其实是有礼貌的
They really do have manners.
没事 我的孩子也这样
It's all right. My kids are the same way.
我们刚吃完 坐吧
We're just finishing up. Please sit down.
好吧 就坐会儿
Oh-- okay. Just for a minute.
爸 给我五块钱去点首歌吧
Dad, five bucks for the jukebox?
什么 不是25美分三首吗
What? What happened to three plays for a quarter?
作业?
Um... homework?
做完了 爸帮忙的
- Done, Dad helped us. - Oh.
我提早下班了 给
I got off early. Here.
你们要去吗
You want to go, too?
你喝什么
So what are you drinking?
来杯白葡糖酒
I'll have a white wine.
我不用了 谢啦
I'm good, thanks.
是真的吗
So it's true?
你戒酒了?
You quit drinking?
我还偶尔喝点啤酒
Well, I have a beer now and again.
没什么大不了的
No big deal.
Dennis怎样了
How's Dennis:
Dennis还是那个Dennis
Dennis is... Dennis.
忽近忽远的
We're close, we're not.
再看吧
You know, we'll see.
- Beadie好吗 - 很好
- How's Beadie? - We're good.
孩子们有我的电话 不过...
- The kids have my number, but... - Mmm.
如果我知道你能成熟起来...
If I had known you were gonna grow up to be a grownup...
靠 伙计
Pssh, man.
我告诉他做正确的事
And I'm the one that told him to do the right thing
去跟那家伙谈谈
and go talk to the man.
现在看来根本不是那么回事
It don't seem that way now, do it?
我是说 该从Marlo的角度看问题
I mean, yo, you got to look at it from Marlo's point of view.
这跟Wallace有什么区别
I mean, how this different from Wallace?
因为Stringer说了Wallace告密
Because Stringer said Wallace snitched.
Kevin也可能告密了
Yo. Kevin might have snitched too.
伙计 他没有
Man, but he didn't.
我们必须做掉Wallace!
And we had to do Wallace!
Marlo认为他必须做掉Kevin
Yo, Marlo thought he had to do Kevin.
他没告密
Man. But he didn't.
我很肯定
That's what I'm saying.
- 他是个冷血的混球 - 这是个冷血的世界 Bodie
- He's a cold motherfucker. - It's a cold world, Bodie.
你还说世界在变暖呢 伙计
Thought you said it was getting warmer, nigger.
世界往一个方向 人往另一个方向 伙计
World going one way, people another, yo.
Elton Brand 你知道他吗
Now, Elton Brand-- what you know about him?
不知道吧
Nothing. You see?
Bug 你见到你爸了吗
Bug, you seen your daddy?
去商店了
Went to the store.
- 你去哪 - 我去找他
- Where you going? - I'm gonna look for him.
你找不到的
You ain't gonna find him.
为什么
Why not?
因为他不会回来了
Because he ain't coming back.
谢了
Thanks.
为什么
What's this about?
你不知道吗
Like you don't know.
伙计 我那么久没回家了 不会惹上谁
Man, I ain't been home long enough to get in somebody's shit.
你喜欢男孩吗 混球
You like boys, motherfucker?
- 什么 - 男孩 你喜欢干他们吗
- What? - Boys. You like fucking them?
伙计 我喜欢女的 行吗 屁股
Man, I like pussy. All right? Booty.
我现在跟个女的同居
Living with a woman now.
她有孩子吗
She got kids?
我没动过他们! 谁跟你们说的
I ain't touch them kids! Who told you that?
我知道你要说什么
I know what you're saying,
但你在里面时可没女人
but when you're on the inside, ain't no pussy.
是啊 靠 你进去过
Well, yeah, shit. You've been inside.
但男人总得发泄啊 了解我的意思吧
Man got to bust his nut, know what I'm saying?
了解
I do.
靠 你都不等把他弄进屋里
Damn. You didn't even wait to get the motherfucker in the house.